CONTACT



+971 54 304 1339 (UAE)



+91 9477321 726 (India)



hmtjha@gmail.com



Flat – 1707, Al Jazeera Tower, Hamdan Street Abu Dhabi

SOCIAL

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/hmtjha

KEY ACHIEVEMENT

- IIT JEE RANK -7194
- AIEEE RANK 218
- GATE Qualified
- Coached underprivilaged students for Engineering Entrance Exam for free by associating with a National NGO.
- Prepared the budget under many head so as to help the management in deciding the areas for cutting down the cost.

Hemant Jha

M.E – Environmental Engg (J.U) B.E – Civil Engg (J.U)



CURRICULUM VITAE

PERSONAL STATEMENT

An alumnus from one of the top 10 universities of India (among the top 600 in world). Physically fit and able to work on-site and at remote locations. Having over three years of experience in core construction companies working from its initial stages. I have an engineering exposure which has helped me in honoring my technical, decision-making and co-ordination skills. I aspire to apply these concepts, which I have acquired through my studies and work to the organisation as well as hone my skills so as to effectively add to my knowledge.

WORK EXPERIENCE

MIS and Costing Engineer

July 2012- Aug 2013

AFCONS INFRASTRUCTURE LTD,

Kolkata

Worked in the Planning Department (MIS and COSTING) in the construction of "Elevated Viaduct of Kolkata Metro Rail" between New Garia to Airport worth 446 crores.

Responsibility:

- Made the Annual Budget, Schedules & DWP for the Financial Year (2013-2014) of the Kolkata Metro Rail Project for 10km stretch.
- Doing Weekly Planning, Monthly Planning, 3 months rolling program.
- Implementation of ISO procedures in planning Dept.
- Estimation of quantity and cost Estimation from drawings.
- Preparation of BBS.
- Making of schedules for the progress of the various activities of project.
- Preparation of Daily progress report, monthly progress report.
- Monitoring of the progress of the project on day to day basis.
- Implementation of SAP and Primavera in Planning related works.
- Preparing Method Statements for different activities that are carried out in the project.
- Preparation of reconciliation statements of steel and other construction materials.

Project Engineer

M/S AKALABYA CONSTRUCTION

July 2016- May 2017

SYNDICATE, Kolkata

Worked in HSCL project in 02 BN NDRF AT Haringhata, Nadia.

Responsibility:

- Project management at every stage.
- Initiation of drawing-Submission of drawing-technical clarification during approval-release to production.
- To understand the project situation, challenges and providing proper solutions
- Undertaking technical and feasibility studies including site investigations.
- Prepared pre-execution engineering cost estimates & budgets.
- Work plan schedules & milestone.
- Quality control & Risk mitigation.
- Ensuring Quality Assurance Plan during execution.
- Liaising with clients and a variety of professionals including architects and subcontractors.
- Resolving design and development problems.

SKILLS

- Planning
- Site Management
- Costing
- Q/S
- MIS
- Client management

STRENGTHS

- Self-confidence.
- Commitment to work.
- Professional attitude
- Good communication skill.
- Excellent analytical abilities.
- Ability to lead as well as follow.

LANGUAGES KNOWN

- English (R, W, S)
- Hindi (R, W, S)
- Maithili (R, W, S)
- Bengali (R, W, S)

MEMBERSHIPS

- Member of Rotary Club
- Actively involved in Toast Master Club

Project Engineer

M/S AKALABYA CONSTRUCTION SYNDICATE, Kolkata

May 2017 present

Construction of (G+4) Residential Apartment Project at Baranagar, Kolkata, West Bengal.

Responsibility:

- Daily tracking of Project progress against goals and objectives with reference to manpower deployed, approved budgets and timelines, contractor progress of work
- Co-ordinating in Material & Machinery management and deployment.
- Safety management compliance and following ISO documentation & statutory requirements
- Inspecting of works at site.
- Inspecting of quality of materials
- Reviewing schematic drawing and designs for conttruction.
- Coordinating with contractor and engineers in processing monthly reports to make sure that all
 information is incorporated in the report
- Ensuring safety complaince of all the workers.
- Estimating of project materials quantity from BBS and drawing.
- Ensuring procurement of materials for construction works to prevent any delay.
- Checking the bill as per the work done done on site.

EDUCATION

M.E. (Civil Engineering) - CGPA-8.0 2014-2016

 $Specialization-Environmental\ Engineering.$

Jadavpur University, Kolkata

B.E. (Civil Engineering) - CGPA - 6.7 2008-2012

Jadavpur University, Kolkata

AISSCE(XII) - 1st Div. - 78% 2007

Kendriya Vidyalaya, Fort William, Kolkata

AISSE (X) -1St Div. -84% 2005

D.A.V. Public School, Kolkata

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Planning
- Budgeting
- Scheduling
- Monitoring

- Quantity surveying
- Asset management
- Risk analysis and mitigation
- Documentation

COMPUTER & IT SKILLS

- Languages: Fortran, C, C++
- Software: AUTOCAD, MS Office, SAP, Primavera, MS Project.

PROJECT

- Quantity estimation of a 1 floor Hospital building.
- Design of an industrial factory shed.
- Design of a (G+11) earthquake resistant building.
- Design of Stack for a factory for environmental pollution prevention.
- Presentation on "River Meandering and erosion" and its prevention.
- Presentation on "Analysis of Indeterminate structures".
- Design of Sewer Line of a Township.
- Report on the "Air Quality Index (AQI) Of Kolkata"
- Seminar presentation on the "Energy Efficient Buildings".

REFERENCES



Vidyut Pradhan Manager Commercial -Leasing IndoSpace - Mumbai



Anand Swarup Contract & procurement Engineer-CMC-OC ZADCO – Abu Dhabi

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- Making robots
- Reading books
- Swimming
- Cycling
- Current affairs

MASTER'S DEGREE THESIS

"Water and Soil Quality Monitoring Around Dhapa Landfill Site for Human Health Risk Assessment".

- Evaluate existing condition of hydro and pedosphere environmental quality.
- Risk assessment of human health in neighboring areas.
- Application of risks models.

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENT

- Participated in JU Annual Tech Fest, SRIJAN and got 3rd position in the I-Design event
- Participated in JU annual Tech Fest SRIJAN and got 1st position in the manual robotics event.
- Participated in JU annual Tech Fest SRIJAN and got 3rd position in the debate event.
- Worked with Indian Cultural Association teaching underprivileged students for JEE Exam.

INTERNSHIP& TRAINING

- Did internship in STUP Consultant Pvt. Ltd office doing concrete design for residential buildings.
- Did summer training in the "Eden City Township Project" under NKS Realtors in their Maheshtalla housing complex site inspections.
- Did a course on "AutoCAD with Auto LISP" at Computer Aided Design Centre, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Jadavpur University.

PERSONAL PROFILE

Name	Hemant Jha
Fathers Name	Kanhaiya Kumar Jha
D.O. B	6th June 1989
Sex	Male
Marital Status	Unmarried
Nationality	Indian
Passport No	N6995186
Address	Flat – 1707, Al Jazeera Tower, Hamdan Street,
	Abu Dhabi - UAE
Contact No	+971 54 304 1339
Driving License	Valid Indian LMV License
Email ID	hmtjha@gmail.com